you guys haven't seen this all over the
place someone even emailed it to me
asking me to solve it so let's just
solve it so this thing is a square
they're telling us that right there now
we have three triangles that we know the
areas and then we have this triangle we
don't know the area since it's a square
all the sides are congruent so I'm going
to call each of the sides X so this
green portion right here I'm going to
call it Y which means this yellow
portion would be the whole thing x minus
y but let's call this blue portion Z and
that would make this yellow portion
equal to x minus Z so let's look at this
green triangle the area of a triangle is
one half base times height so we can say
one half x times Y is equal to the area
which is four and then if we look at
this blue one it'd be one half the x
times Z is equal to two and then for
this last triangle it'd be one half this
thing times this thing equals three I
don't really like fractions so let's
multiply both sides of all three of
these equations by two all these
one-halves will go away and the right
sides are just going to double we'll
have eight four and six so now let's
focus on these top two equations let's
divide both sides of both equations by X
this this X over X cancels this X over X
cancels and these just become 8 over X
and 4 over X so now let's do some
substitution for this Z I want to plug
in 4 over X and for this y I want to
plug in 8 over X so now on the left hand
side let's distribute x times x is x
squared x times negative 8 over X is
negative x times 8 over X these two x's
will cancel so it's just negative 8. and
then this times this is negative x times
4 over X but these X's cancel again to
give us negative 4. and this times this
is a negative times a negative which is
positive it's going to be a fraction or
4 times 8 is 32 and x times x is x
squared and this is all still equal to
6. well negative 8 negative 4 can
combine to negative 12. I don't really
like fractions so let's get rid of this
x squared in the denominator by
multiplying both sides by x squared x
squared times x squared is X to the
fourth x squared times negative 12 is
negative 12x squared x squared times 32
over x squared is just going to be 32
and then 6 times x squared is 6X squared
and then we get subtract 6X squared from
both sides which will make this side 0
and this side would be negative 18x
squared and now we want to factor this
since it's set equal to zero so x to the
fourth here means we want an x squared
and an x squared and then we want two
numbers that add to negative 18 and
multiply to 32. that's going to be
negative 16 and negative 2. this plus
this is negative 18 and this times this
is positive 32. now since this times
this equals zero we can set each of
these equal to zero we can add 16 to
both sides or add 2 to both sides
negative 16 and positive 16 cancel and 0
plus 16 is 16. negative 2 plus 2 cancel
and 0 plus 2 is 2. let's smush things
together and take the square root square
root of x squared is the absolute value
of x and square root of 16 is 4 square
of x and the square root of 2 is square
root of 2. since X represents the length
it must be positive so these absolute
values are not necessary so we know X is
either 4 or square root of 2 and let's
check them so if x is equal to 4 the
area of the square would be equal to 4
Square squared and if x is square root
of 2 then the area would be square root
of 2 squared 4 squared is equal to 16
and square root of 2 squared is equal to
2. so the area of this green triangle
right here is four there's no way the
area of the whole Square can be just two
so we can disregard that value so we
know that the area of the entire square
is equal to 16. so we can add this 2
plus the 3 plus the 4 plus the question
mark and set it equal to 16. and after
we subtract 9 from both sides we get the
question mark is equal to seven that
means the area of this red triangle is
equal to seven centimeters squared we
can blow it up and put a box around it
how exciting